ABDULLAH ASHRAF

Islamabad, Pakistan | (+92) 344 5434240 | m.aashraf01@outlook.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Experienced MERN Stack Developer known for creating visually stunning, responsive web apps. Aiming for a career in the software industry, I bring a strong problem-solving acumen, will power for continuous learning and professional growth, and a commitment to exceeding expectations.

EDUCATION

National University of Sciences and Technology, NUST

Islamabad, Pakistan

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

November 2020 - June 2024

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fiverr Remote

MERN Stack Developer | Level 2 Seller

February 2023 – Present

- Completed 29 web app development orders with a 4.9-star rating, consistently meeting deadlines and client requirements.
- Boosted company productivity by 40% with a MERN Stack ERP system, optimizing management and reporting.
- Increased sales by 25% for an E-Commerce plate maker with an online store using MERN Stack.

EMR Chains Islamabad, Pakistan

Intern - MERN Stack Developer

July 2023 – August 2023

- Mentored a team of 3 interns in React JS and Node.js, fostering a collaborative learning environment.
- Enhanced company website's front-end, making it responsive and user-friendly with Next JS.

SoftThrive Remote

Intern - Frontend Developer

June 2022 – August 2022

- Collaborated with the Frontend team, contributed to the development and maintenance of innovative web components while implementing rigorous unit testing practices.

Personal Projects

Development of an Accounting software for an Educational Institute using NEXT JS

In Progress

Personal Project

- Designed and integrated document generation features using React PDF Renderer and Sheet JS for streamlined invoice creation and Excel spreadsheet management.

Development of a Movie watching app using Next JS, Tailwind CSS and Socket.io

June 2024

Personal Project

- Developed an interactive app for watching movies/tv-shows. Creators can upload/add external links for the media items. Media items are being stored in Cloudinary and meta data of these videos is then stored in MongoDB.
- Implemented real-time Likes, Views and comments updating using WebSocket.
- Implemented user's watch history, most watched genre, user's favorite movies database for customized content recommendation.

IoT based weather forecasting using Next JS and LSTM model

February 2024

 Collected data of temperatures and humidity using DHT-11 sensor and feed it in google sheet using ESP32 microcontroller and IFTTT as middleware. Preprocessed the data, such as filling up missing values, extracted valuable insights from the data using Pandas and NumPy libraries. Trained the model and rendered the predicted values and actual values on NEXT JS App.

Intellectobot - An AI bot developed using Next JS and OpenAI API Key

September 2023

Personal Project | Link

Semester Project | Link

- Utilized OpenAI's API key for generating responses and Next JS Edge functions for streaming responses.

Development of a real-time chatting application using MERN Stack

July 2023

Personal Project | <u>Link</u>

- Developed a real-time chatting application for anonymous messaging. The messages disappear and are deleted from the database after 24 hours.

Development of Home Automation IoT system using React JS, Firebase and ESP 32

June 2023

Semester Project | Link

- Managed automated control of various household elements. Developed the Web App using React JS and Firebase for user authentication and real-time database storage.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C++
- Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React JS, Next JS, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Next UI
- Backend Development: Node JS, Express JS
- Databases: MongoDB, Firebase
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Cloud Services: AWS, Google Cloud, IBM Cloud
- Micro-controllers: Arduino, ESP32, Raspberry pi